



Manav Kaushal

Email address: manavdkaushal@gmail.com

○ WhatsApp Messenger: +919833080299

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/manavkaushal

• Home: Globalcity, Virar West Palghar, Near Mumbai, 401303 Palghar (India)

ABOUT ME

I am into developing Business applications, Data structures, Designing Software to help B2B, B2C communicate better and achieve set goals.

An industry hardened warhorse with 20+ years of experience. I like to learn new Tech and guide my team complete their sprints.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Java Team Leader

Finexcore Software Solutions [01/04/2023 - 12/09/2023]

City: Mumbai Country: India

- Led a team of 5 Java developers in implementation of Finastra LoanIQ onsite in Saudi, resulting in a 25% increase in efficiency.
- Coordinated daily stand-up meetings and conducted code reviews to ensure team meet project deadlines and quality standards.
- Implemented agile methodologies, including Scrum to streamline project management processes and improve team collaboration.
- Mentored team members through Code Reviews, best practices, testing, and debugging software, resulting in a 15% decrease in bug fixes post-release.

Team Leader

Hiddenbrains Software Solutions [01/04/2022 - 28/02/2023]

City: Mumbai Country: India

- Delegated daily tasks to team members to optimize group productivity.
- Developed strategies for problem solving and conflict resolution among team members.
- Assigned projects and disctributed tasks to team members as per area of expertise.
- Reviewed completed work to verify consistency, quality and conformance.

Team Leader

TP Connects - Dubai [18/03/2021 - 28/02/2022]

City: Dubai

Country: United Arab Emirates

- Airline Ticket Booking System TP Connects (Dubai)
- Designed and Developed the Order Booking module for the Airline Booking system at TP-Connects.
- I was entrusted to maintain the complete Passenger Booking, Order Management, Supplier Management with History of changes and Reporting.

- Handled a team of five junior Java developers to develop various modules of the system.
- I was also involved in Code reviews, quality checks, bug fixing and functional testing of my modules.

Associate Manager

Bristlecone [01/03/2020 - 31/12/2020]

City: Mumbai Country: India

- Audit Management System Mahindra & Mahindra (Mumbai, Pune)
- Developed with a team of four Java developers the Product & Process Audit system at Mahindra.
- I wrote the Core Business APIs, also designed the UI dashboard, pop-up Alert system & Reports.
- I was the SPOC for all the Mahindra Plants and the IT team for Audit system.
- I was also involved in system decision making, process flows and use to attend all Mgmt meetings.

Senior Project Manager

Locationguru India Pvt. Ltd. [01/05/2018 - 31/07/2019]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

- Managed project scope, timeline and budget in alignment with company objectives.
- Delivered high level of service to clients to extend relationship and encourage further projects.
- Established best practices for managing complex projects successfully.
- Coordinated resources across multiple departments and teams to ensure successful completion of projects.

Project Manager

Intellect Design Arena [01/12/2014 - 30/09/2016]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

- Developed and maintained project plans, timelines, and budgets.
- Managed multiple projects with competing deadlines simultaneously.
- Provided guidance to team members regarding tasks assigned to them.
- Created and implemented processes to ensure successful completion of projects.
- Coordinated resources across multiple departments and teams as needed for successful completion of projects.

Project manager

Byzan Systems Pvt. Ltd. [01/04/2013 – 30/11/2014]

City: Mumbai Country: India

- Managed multiple projects with competing deadlines simultaneously.
- Developed and maintained project plans, timelines, and budgets.
- Built and established strong partnerships with teams, vendors and contractors.
- Monitored progress of each project to ensure timely delivery of deliverables in accordance with established quality standards.

Team Leader

Alifsystems Pvt. Ltd. [01/05/2001 – 30/04/2013]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

- Back Office Accounting System (BOSS) Alifsystems (Mumbai)
- Designed & Developed Hotel Accounting systems using Oracle Forms & Reports D2k 9i at Alifsystems.
- I lead a team of 15 Oracle developers to convert their Foxpro 2.6 apps into Oracle Forms & Reports.
- I developed core Business libraries, wrote backend Stored procedures, tax calculations for various modules and Reports.

- I used Oracle Database 9i, 11g, Oracle Application Server 10g, Oracle PL-SQL, Triggers and procedures, Oracle SQL and more.
- I also later upgraded their apps to Java, Spring, Hibernate, Mysql and JSP based web applications.
- I trained a team of 8 Java developers to migrate their client server based apps to Java Web apps.
- I touched up every dept of SDLC during my 12+ years of work at Alif. Design, Dev, Impl, Training, R&D

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

AWS Cloud Computing Fundamental - Certificate

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/02/2024 – 29/02/2024]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-TFMJEEJJ

Asynchronous Messaging - RabbitMQ

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/02/2024 - 29/02/2024]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-FOZ9KT74

Project Management PMP Preparatory

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/02/2024 - 29/02/2024]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-D2VYZ7BO

Java, Spring Boot With JWT

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/10/2023 - 31/12/2023]

City: MUMBAI
Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-OH9XY3KH

Oracle SQL And PL/SQL Certification

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/12/2023 - 31/01/2024]

City: MUMBAI
Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-HBVB63IR

Certificate in Computing

IGNOU [01/03/2003 - 30/04/2004]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: http://ignou.ac.in

Advance Diploma in Software Engineering - ADSE

Aptech Computer Education - Mumbai [01/03/2001 - 30/04/2003]

City: MUMBAI
Country: India

Bachelor of Commerce

University of Mumbai [01/04/1996 – 30/04/1999]

City: MUMBAI Country: India Website: https://mu.ac.in/

Agile Project Management & Scrum

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/01/2024 - 31/01/2024]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-HQ5O3HEO

Apache Cassandra - No-SQL database

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/02/2024 - 02/2024]

City: MUMBAI
Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-T1XA5WSK

Mastering MySql Database

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/11/2023 - 30/11/2023]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-5C2PCCXC

Azure DevOps Fundamentals & Collaboration Course

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/01/2021 - 01/03/2024]

City: Mumbai Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-9K1UN82D

Docker for Java & Spring Boot - Certification

Tutorialspoint - E-Learning Institute [01/03/2021 - 10/03/2024]

City: MUMBAI Country: India

Website: https://www.tutorialspoint.com/market/certificate.jsp/TP-3K5M1476

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Hindi

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Html, Java, CSS / Node Js (JavaScript) / Cassandra (NoSQL) / RabbitMQ / Kafka / Java with SpringBoot / Web services Microservices / REST/API / Oracle PL/SQL, Oracle DB / Managing Databases (MySQL) / JavaScript - JQuery / Programming html5 / Platform: AWS Cloud / Attended PMP preparation Course / Agile-Scrum / Junit, Mockito / Git, Git Hub, SVN / Good knowledge in working with ORM tools like Spring ORM and Hibernate / Java, J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, EJB, JPA, JDBC, JMS / HTML5, / good HTML ,CSS, JS, JQuery, Bootstrap skills / Microsoft Fundamenlats Azure -Cloud / Kubernetes, Docker-Swarm

MANAGED CLIENTELE

Hotels

JW Marriots, Radissons, Inter-Continental, Le-Meridien, Leela Group, Hafele, Oberois, Lemontree, GVK, Novotel, Taj-Africa, Taj-Seychelles, Taj-Maldives, Taj-Bhutan, Taj-Colombo

Banking

Bank of America, Citi Bank, HDFC, ICICI, SCB, Yes Bank, DCB, Barclays, HSBC

Airlines

Oman Airlines - UAE, Gulf Air - Dubai, Flight Centre - Australia, British Airways

Telecom

Reliance Digital, Reliance Grocery, Vodafone, Reliance JIO, Airtel

Automobiles

Mahindra Auto - Pune, Mahindra Auto - Mumbai

Payment & Social Networking Apps

Quickteller (Interswitch) - Nigeria, LoanIQ (Finastra) - Saudi, Payroll & Income Tax (Alifsystems) - Mumbai

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Management & Leadership skills

- **Software Development**: developed Applications from scratch. UML diagrams, wireframing
- Product Lead: key role in Product design, enhancement, maintenance. Technical designing.
- Project Management: qualities of leadership with discipline. Converting Business logic to ER.
- Strong communication skills: have handled Clientele across globe, Dev. Teams (15+ members)
- **Development Team Management :** being hands-on helps to build & maintain a productive Team.
- Client & Stakeholder Management: on-site work in many countries helps to handle Clientele as SPOC.